# Franger Centeno Briceño

# Software Developer

Lisbon, Portugal

### **ABOUT ME**

I am a Software Developer with 6 years of experience but my focus has been on Front End. My skills are based on JavaScript and Frameworks and libraries. I had the opportunity to live and work in Peru for 5 years where I could work with a multicultural team before coming to Portugal. My goal is to keep growing as a Developer to become a Lead or Manager in the future.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Crehana, Lima - Peru - Front End Developer

JUL 2020 - DEC 2022

- I collaborated with a multidisciplinary team in the Growth team making improvements to the main landings of the company, in the authentication, ecommerce and blog pages. Also, I developed A/B tests to test new functionalities within the platform. My non-product responsibilities included contributions to our design system.
- I have worked with technologies such as React.js, Next.js, Typescript, GraphQL, Styled Components, Tailwind, Jest, React Testing Library and Cypress with TDD and agile methodology.

Nodos Digital, Lima - Peru - Front End Developer

MAR 2019 - JUN 2020

- I collaborated with a multidisciplinary team in projects for important clients such as Pinturas Vencedor, BBVA, Real Plaza, Brein (Breca Group), Clínica AVIVA, Monumental Music Callao making landing pages, forms, and CMS.
- I have worked with technologies such as React.js, Redux, Vue.js,
  Typescript, GraphQL, Jest, Node.js, React Testing Library with agile methodology.

Optima Marketing Systems, Lima - Perú - Junior Full Stack Developer

DIC 2017 - OCT 2018

 Junior Full Stack Developer in the OPTIMA CMR project, the main project of the company in which he bases his income and in which user data is handled.  I have worked with technologies such as JQuery, Vue.js, PHP, Javascript and MySql.

#### **EXPERIENCIA FREELANCER**

#### Crehana, Remote - Front End Developer

FEB 2023 - CURRENTLY

- I work directly and autonomously with the Growth and SEO team on the platform's blog making improvements, bug fixes and implementing new features.
- React.js, Next.js, Typescript, GraphQL, Styled Components, Tailwind, Jest, React Testing Library and Cypress.

#### Tecno Makers SAS, Remote - Front End Developer

DIC 2018 - FEB 2019

- I collaborated with a multidisciplinary team in the CMS of Discovery Channel LATAM and all extensions such as Animal Planet, Food Network, among others, where the management of large amounts of images, videos and information was optimized.
- I have worked with technologies such as React.js, Redux, Typescript, APIs, Jest, React Testing Library and SCSS with testing and agile methodology.

#### JLR Analytics, Lima - Peru - Full Stack Developer

NOV 2018 - FEB 2019

- Full Stack Developer in creation of an internal system with geolocation for a client in the logistics sector.
- I have worked with Node.js, PHP, JQuery, React.js, MySql.

#### Peru Hop, Lima - Peru - Front End Developer

AGO DE 2018 - SEP DE 2018

- I contributed my knowledge for the creation of the frontend of the company's internal use software. Software for hotels, transportation and restaurants. The team was only frontend and we used Firebase services.
- I have worked with technologies such as React.js, Redux, APIs and SCSS.

#### **TECHNOLOGIES AND SKILLS**

#### **Technologies**

- JavaScript
- React.js
- Next.js
- Typescript
- Jest
- React Testing Library Cypress
- CSS-SCSS
- Tailwind
- Styles Components Redux
- React Router
- React Query
- GraphQL
- Node.js
- MySQL

## **Soft and Hards Skills**

- Programming languages
- Database
- App architecture
- UX/UI
- Leadership
- Innovation
- Creativity
- Organization
- Empathy
- Proactivity
- Teamwork

### **EDUCATION**

Simon Bolivar experimental university, Caracas, Venezuela - Bachelor's Degree in Administration, mention in Computer Science

Bachelor's Degree in Administration, mention in Computer Scienc 2022

U.E.D. Juan Pablo II, Caracas, Venezuela- Financial Administration

Technician

2011

## **CURSOS**

Crehana Microdegree, Online - Project Management

2022

Cibertec, Lima - Peru- Angular 8

2020

Cibertec, Lima - Peru- Java Fundamentals

2019

# **IDIOMAS**

- Spanish (Native)
- English (B1/B2)
- Portuguese (Basic Learning)